<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IPXACT on Techiedeepdive</title>
    <link>/tags/ipxact/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IPXACT on Techiedeepdive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ipxact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IPXACT parser To Tree -- One way to avoid XML</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/03/ipxact-parser-to-tree-one-way-to-avoid-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023/03/ipxact-parser-to-tree-one-way-to-avoid-xml/</guid>
      <description>In older post, I went through ipxactral (poor man&amp;rsquo;s RAL generator). It seems only logical to extract the part where i process XML and make dedicated module for that. I hear someone shouting, isn&amp;rsquo;t XML a tree already? My answer is I HATE XML, So I will do whatever to avoid dealing with XML.
Jumping right into it, IPXACTTree just takes path to ixact file.
t = IPXACTTree(args.ipxactfile) The heavy lifting is done here to create the tree starting from root and recursively going through the nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviving old project - IPXACT to UVM RAL Generator - ipxactral</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/01/reviving-old-project-ipxact-to-uvm-ral-generator-ipxactral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022/01/reviving-old-project-ipxact-to-uvm-ral-generator-ipxactral/</guid>
      <description>This was a weekend project back in 2020 to build IPXACT parser and UVM register Model generator. As an example of the lack of imagination at that time, I decided to call it &amp;lsquo;ipaxctral&amp;rsquo;. Creative?! I know!
IPXACT I will just copy/paste the wiki here. But full Spec is on Accellera website
 IP-XACT is an XML format that defines and describes individual, re-usable electronic circuit designs (individual pieces of intellectual property, or IPs) to facilitate their use in creating integrated circuits (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
