<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>qemu on Techiedeepdive</title>
    <link>/tags/qemu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in qemu on Techiedeepdive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/qemu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Qemu - Data object exchange DOE</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/04/qemu-data-object-exchange-doe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023/04/qemu-data-object-exchange-doe/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick write-up about Qemu DOE emulation. DOE is part of PCIe and CXL extended capabilities. Technically, It&amp;rsquo;s optional but is important part of IDE starting gen5.
Starting with cxl_usp_read_config is one of the places where pcie_doe_read_config is called. It seems it&amp;rsquo;s only supported with CXL which kinda matches what kernel implements. If it&amp;rsquo;s DOE extended address, it will fall back to pci_default_read_config.
static uint32_t cxl_usp_read_config(PCIDevice *d, uint32_t address, int len) { CXLUpstreamPort *usp = CXL_USP(d); uint32_t val; if (pcie_doe_read_config(&amp;amp;usp-&amp;gt;doe_cdat, address, len, &amp;amp;val)) { return val; } return pci_default_read_config(d, address, len); } pcie_doe_read_config reads the fields when address matches the DW in DOW extended configuration address space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qemu - PCIe SRIOV and virtual function</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/04/qemu-pcie-sriov-and-virtual-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023/04/qemu-pcie-sriov-and-virtual-function/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick write-up about SRIOV and virtual functions emulation in Qemu. From link
 SR-IOV is a specification that allows a single Peripheral Component Interconnect Express (PCIe) physical device under a single root port to appear as multiple separate physical devices to the hypervisor or the guest operating system.
SR-IOV uses physical functions (PFs) and virtual functions (VFs) to manage global functions for the SR-IOV devices. PFs are full PCIe functions that are capable of configuring and managing the SR-IOV functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qemu PCIe Emulation</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/03/qemu-pcie-emulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023/03/qemu-pcie-emulation/</guid>
      <description>This post is about how qemu emulates PCI devices for guest Kernel. Honestly, I took the scenic road here which is reading the code and setting breakpoints in GDB at interesting places and work my way through the stack trace. Disclaimer, This is a very short post on a complicated topic and huge code base(Qemu). But It&amp;rsquo;s a good start to dig deeper into qemu code (more specifically PCI emulation in qemu)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boot linux in Qemu</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/05/boot-linux-in-qemu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/05/boot-linux-in-qemu/</guid>
      <description>This is quick guide to compile linux kernel and minimal boot in Qemu.
Compiling linux kernel To compile linux kernel, you will need .config to configure the build. To generate default .config:
make defconfig if you are planning to upgrade the kernel version on your machine, you need to use the current config to generate compatible configuration
cp /boot/config-`kernel version` ./config make oldconfig Creating busybox initramfs mkinitramfs creates minimal busybox file system with busybox unix commands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
