<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hft on Techiedeepdive</title>
    <link>/tags/hft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hft on Techiedeepdive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/hft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HFT - OUCH protocol primer</title>
      <link>/posts/2025/06/hft-ouch-protocol-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2025/06/hft-ouch-protocol-primer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is primer about OUCH protocol which is Nasdaq low latency protocol for trading companies to send trading orders to the exchange. These are snippets from the specification document:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NASDAQ accepts limit orders from system participants and executes matching orders when possible. Non-matching orders&#xA;may be added to the NASDAQ Limit Order Book, a database of available limit orders, where they wait to be matched in price-&#xA;time priority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OUCH is a simple protocol that allows NASDAQ participants to enter, replace, and cancel orders and receive executions. It is&#xA;intended to allow participants and their software developers to integrate NASDAQ into their proprietary trading systems or to&#xA;build custom front ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HFT - ITCH protocol primer</title>
      <link>/posts/2025/06/hft-itch-protocol-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2025/06/hft-itch-protocol-primer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been dabbling with HFT for few weeks now. So, I thought to go through of the protocols such ITCH and OUCH. This post is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nasdaqtrader.com/content/technicalsupport/specifications/dataproducts/NQTVITCHSpecification.pdf&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ITCH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nasdaq TotalView ITCH is a direct data feed product offered by The Nasdaq Stock Market, LLC. This specification covers&#xA;both the software and hardware (FPGA) versions of the feed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nasdaq will broadcast the TotalView ITCH FPGA feed from the U.S. primary data center facility in Carteret,&#xA;New Jersey in the MoldUDP64 protocol option only. Given the unshaped network traffic, Nasdaq is requiring firms to&#xA;have 10 Gb or 40 Gb network connection into the Carteret, NJ data center to obtain the TotalView ITCH FPGA feed.&#xA;As with the software version of the feed, the TotalView ITCH FPGA feed will be comprised of a series of sequenced&#xA;order messages. Outside of the fact that the FPGA data delivery is unthrottled or unshaped at the network level, the&#xA;TotalView-•-ITCH payload will be the same for both versions of the TotalView-•-ITCH 5.0 data formats. TotalView ITCH&#xA;FPGA product is guaranteed to disseminate payload messages in the same exact order as the software-•-based version&#xA;of the TotalView ITCH feed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
