<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Techiedeepdive</title>
    <link>/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Techiedeepdive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New computer! Who dis?</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/02/new-computer-who-dis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2023/02/new-computer-who-dis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People talk about the smell of a new car, but nobody talks about the smell of new computer. The smell of plastic and potential :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently retired my veteran Ideapad after battery, battery socket and eventually screen failed. safe to say, I got my money worth out of it. Honestly, I am surprised it lasted 7 years!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reset in peace(RIP), my friend!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to get another Ideapad. After research for few days, I found what I am looking for. I3 and decent RAM and It&amp;rsquo;s not going to break the bank.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purpose lost in search of limelight, They said!</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/02/purpose-lost-in-search-of-limelight-they-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2023/02/purpose-lost-in-search-of-limelight-they-said/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: This is a joke/rant post. If sarcasm is not your thing, Please, skip this one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was told something that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to respond to. I didn&amp;rsquo;t say anything at the time, but it bugged me for few hours then I thought of something and didn&amp;rsquo;t think about since(Good will hunting?!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, someone said&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your purpose is lost in search of limelight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took me few seconds to parse and process the statement. English is my second language and the wording didn&amp;rsquo;t seem right to me. What in the name of google-translate does this mean?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Irish tax calculation using Python Jupyter notebook</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/01/irish-tax-calculation-using-python-jupyter-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2023/01/irish-tax-calculation-using-python-jupyter-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For few years now I have using google sheets to keep track of taxes and check payroll tax calculations (trust but verify, Right?).&#xA;Anyway, I decided to move to Jupyter notebook/python combo to do the calculations. This is small code to calculate the Irish tax (PAYE, USC, PRSI). I have a bigger dashboard with ESPP, RSU and bonus but I thought it would be an overkill here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;jupyter&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Jupyter&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#jupyter&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start a Jupyter notebook:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DVcon random thoughts - Multiple discovery!</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/12/dvcon-random-thoughts-multiple-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2022/12/dvcon-random-thoughts-multiple-discovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever read a paper or while talking to someone, and you think this is a good idea. It&amp;rsquo;s really good that you had it before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During DVcon this year, I attended a lot of presentations and had great discussions with awesome people. It is really weird how we sometimes have the same idea at the same time. Like exactly the same idea!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apparently, This has a name &amp;ldquo;Multiple discovery&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget Schrodinger&#39;s cat, Let me tell you about Schrodinger&#39;s visa</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/11/forget-schrodingers-cat-let-me-tell-you-about-schrodingers-visa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2022/11/forget-schrodingers-cat-let-me-tell-you-about-schrodingers-visa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know about Schrodinger&amp;rsquo;s cat, Well, At least whatever I remember from that undergrad physics. It&amp;rsquo;s a thought experiment that goes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He imagined a box containing a radioactive atom, a vial of poison and a cat. Governed by quantum rules, the radioactive atom can either decay or not at any given moment. There’s no telling when the moment will come, but when it does decay, it breaks the vial, releases the poison and kills the cat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The gamification of unfinished side projects</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/10/the-gamification-of-unfinished-side-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2022/10/the-gamification-of-unfinished-side-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/bojack.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably, you are wondering what that title means and what Bojack Horseman is doing here. Actually, This started as a serious question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to finish something when the reason to do that is elusive?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thing is I have this bad habit of starting things purely for intellectual curiosity,So, I ended up with hundreds of README, dozens of git repos, half-written paper abstracts and earmarked books lurking around for years. There is too much to read and learn with very little time to do it. Now, the problem how to finish all of these projects when there is no good reason to start them?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years - Now what?</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/09/10-years-now-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2022/09/10-years-now-what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/now_what.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 AM Saturday 17 Sep 2022&#xA;Cork City&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This might be the bad pizza I had earlier talking (BOOM Jerry Maguire reference!),but This year marks ten years since I graduated and I find myself thinking about this question, Should i retire, move to Peru, change my name to Javier, grow a ponytail, start Alpaca farm and never touch a computer never again?  Probably Not. I could pull off a ponytail though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recruiting - My 2cents </title>
      <link>/posts/2022/09/recruiting-my-2cents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2022/09/recruiting-my-2cents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been seeing a lot hate towards recruiters these days and i can&amp;rsquo;t really understand why. really Why?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The more I think about it, recruiting is a hard job. I know it may sound simplistic(and I may be totally wrong here), It is a sales job but it is about selling the idea of candidate to a company and selling the idea of company to a candidate. It is about finding the perfect person for the perfect job at the perfect time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commentary on Jerry Maguire mission statement</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/09/commentary-on-jerry-maguire-mission-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2022/09/commentary-on-jerry-maguire-mission-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jerry Maguire is one of my all-time favourite movies. I find the mission statement Jerry wrote in his Miami hotel room the most interesting part. The idea of having a moment of clarity (breakhthrough not a breakdown) is life-changing. He (i know Jerry is not real :) ) wrote a genius document that applies to any profession really not just sports agents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cameron Crowe released the full mission statement on the 20th anniversary at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theuncool.com/2016/04/25/jerry-maguire-mission-statement/&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Jerry reads parts of it in the movie but when I read the whole thing, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe how it spoke to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I blog</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/01/why-i-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2022/01/why-i-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend asked me why I am more active with blog posts recently and It&amp;rsquo;s only fitting to reply with blog post( found it funny too).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thing is, since my undergrad years, I am used to take notes on everything. Lecture notes, project notes, problem sets notes. Probably all engineering students do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to the concept of a README(it has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/README&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; and everyhthing) back in 2011 and I was hooked. So, I have been writing 100&amp;rsquo;s of README on every technical projects i was involved in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
